Mikhail Tregubov

Novosibirsk, Russia

mtregubov.com@gmail.com + www.mtregubov.com + www.linkedin.com/in/mtregubov

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER, MENTOR, TUTOR

More than 10 years of industry experience developing web applications and user interfaces (UI) Expert in JavaScript (10+ years), NodeJS, Express, HTML5 (10+ years), CSS3 (10+ years), React, Redux and other UX technologies.

ABOUT ME

I have been doing professional programming using various programming languages for more than twenty years. Since **2005**, when I first had a chance to try my hand at creating a web project using JavaScript, and until now, I have never parted with this great programming language! I have an expert level of knowledge in Javascript.

Throughout my industry career, I created various corporate web applications for many companies across the world, which included various consumer websites, as well as full-scale web applications of various levels of complexity.

As a presentation layer architect, I led the development of client components for popular sites in several Bay Area startups. Regularly I am a contractor at the University of South California, where I do consulting and maintain several legacy systems.

With a lot of experience, I feel an inner need to share my knowledge and experience in JavaScript with novice and practicing web developers. Currently, I am interested in mentoring, conducting private consultations, doing refactoring, reviewing code for front-end applications, helping to understand web programming, use of JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Flexbox.

I hope that my efforts will help other web developers better understand JavaScript, and maybe even love it. JavaScript combines both simplicity and complexity, incredible flexibility and endless power in its applications. And all of this is open to those who understand **JavaScript**!

SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

- React/Redux app development
- Languages: JavaScript (ES2015+, ES6, etc., with Flow types), TypeScript
- Web: HTML5, CSS3, AJAX, JSON, HTTP/REST API, GraphQL, Progressive Web App - PWA (ServiceWorker)
- JavaScript: NPM, React, Redux, Gulp, Webpack, Babel, Thunk, Saga, Flow, Flexbox, Grid
- Testing: Mocha, Chai, Jest

- Back-end: Node.js, Express, MongoDb
- UX & UI design
- Version control: Git, GitHub, SVN
- Requirement engineering and work with the customer
- Technical proposal development
- Software engineering, specification, testing and validation plan development

EXPERIENCE

2020 – present	USC Center for Systems and Software Engineering, Remote Contractor, Senior Fullstack Web consultant, mentor
2019 – 2020	USC , Remote Contractor, Senior Fullstack Web Developer
2017 – 2019	Rateksib, Remote Contractor, Senior Web Developer
2016 – 2017	Arcadiaswimclub, Remote Contractor, Lead Developer
2015 – 2016	Japan-tool, Remote Contractor, Midle Front-End Developer
2015	Nivapechka, Remote Contractor, Senior Back-End Developer
2014 - 2015	USC , Remote Contractor, Midle Fullstack Web Developer
2014	Scriptonomics, Remote Contractor, Senior Developer
2012 – 2013	VYMA, Remote Contractor, Senior Front-End Developer
2011 – 2012	TurntableFm, Development of a web chat for an audio
	streaming service. Technologies used: JavaScript, Node.js, NPM, MongoDb.
2005 – 2013	OLMI.ltd, Senior Software Engineer

FEATURED PROJECTS

- www.scriptonomics.com online service for highlighting and extracting actor's lines from movie scripts.
- www.nivapechka.com online store and blog about air conditioning in Lada Niva cars (React, Node.is)
- www.arcadiaswimclub.org swim competitions scheduling service for swim clubs (Angular, Bootstrap)
- www.rateksib.ru web-portal one of the largest freight companies in Russia.
- www.vyma.org web-portal for youth music education programs, online tuition and registration processing system (Bootstrap, React, React-Redux, Node.js)
- www.alawebdev.com studio of web design (Node.js)
- www.japan-tool.ru online store, Hitachi Tool focuses on making tools for heavy and challenging materials.
- Websites and blogs:
 - o www.atregubov.com
 - o www.mtregubov.com

EDUCATION

 Frunze State Polytechnic University, Department of Information Technologies, Engineer, Frunze, USSR.